Ravi Shankar Mishra () Featured

CSA, CSSA PEGA Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, C, Core Java, Oracle, MySQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS3, MS SQL Server, Pega PRPC



Current Designation: PEGA Developer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini Technology Services India Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Limited Company: Capgemini Technology Services

Current Location: Kolkata

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Hyderabad, Kolkata

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: PEGA Developer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Core

Java, Oracle, MySQL, HTML, CSS3, MS SQL Server, Pega PRPC

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

4.6 Years of overall experience as Pega Developer.

As a core team member I have involved in many areas of PRPC which include Flow actions, Harnesses, Sections, Activities, Declarative rules and Decision Rules.

Implemented Process Flows and Screen Flows as per user requirement.

Attending daily status calls and fixing bugs.

Having strong experience in design and development of Business Process Management (BPM)

Extensive knowledge in Design, Development, Migration, Deployment and Integration of PRPC.

Skilled in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).

Good Exposure in Banking domain.

Involved in designing application security which involves setting up Access Groups, Access Roles, Operator IDs, Applications,

Organizations, Org Divisions, Org Units and Work Groups.

Designed simple and complex User Interfaces using Harness, Section, Fragment and HTML Property rules for easy navigation, entering, updating, and reviewing for users.

Work Experience

Capgemini Technology Services India Limited as PEGA Developer

Sep 2018 to Till Date

PROJECT: USG PEOPLE BELGIUM PEGA SUPPORT (September 2018- Ongoing)

Client: USG PEOPLE Belgium

Role: Team lead & Senior Pega Developer

Team Size: 4

Description: This ongoing project is built on PEGA version 7.2.2. As a team we are working on all parts of the project.

Such as:

Monitoring everyday Pega and Server logs for issues related to functionality and performances

Fixing minor and major defects

Keeping compliance score upto the mark

Dealing client with their requirements and updates

Performing Lock and Roll tasks on weekly basis

Performing production releases on monthly basis

Providing best possible PEGA practices for better enhancement of current application

Raising Service Request to PEGA support and following up with them for the defects which are critical

Environment: PEGA PRPC Ver. 7.2.2.

Virtusa Consulting Services Private Limited as PEGA Developer

Mar 2016 to Jul 2018

PROJECT: Royal Bank of Canada (Upgrade Project) January 2017 - February 2018

Client: RBC (Royal Bank of Canada)

Role: Senior Developer

Team Size: 6 Description:

The project is about upgrading existing 6 applications to PEGA 7.1.2 version. Which were earlier developed in older

version.

We converted all deprecated controls into new controls and redesigned the applications with new UI. The upgraded application is now compatible with all sort of devices like Desktop, Mobile and tablet.

Environment: PEGA PRPC.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Interacted with Project Manager to understand the business process, identify enhancements and gather Business Requirements.

Creation of flow actions, html rules based on the business requirement.

Worked on Activities in creating the business logic.

Effectively using the Tracer tool and Clipboard to quick fix the defects that we get from Client.

Implemented work flows parts of day to day business operations the workflows are crucial to success of the system.

Designed and implemented complex user interfaces

Implemented various PRPC components like Decision tables, Decision Trees, Data Transforms, Declarative expressions etc.

Worked with testing team to fix the raised defects quickly and accurately.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Birla Institute of Technology (BIT), Ranchi in 2011

PG: MCA (Computers) from Birla Institute of Technology (BIT), Ranchi in 2014

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

P.G Diploma

PEGA Certified System Architect 7.2 (Pega CSA)

PEGA Certified Senior System Architect 7.2(Pega CSSA)

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
ASP.NET	4.0	2015	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
С		2015	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
CORE JAVA			
Oracle 10g, MySQL			
HTML, JavaScript			
CSS3, PHP		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Tomcat, Apache		2020	4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Microsoft SQL Server 2008		2016	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
PEGA PRPC	7.2.2.	2020	4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: RGF Staffing Client: USG People Belgium Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Sep 2018 - Dec 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Project deails with Human Resource management system. Built on PEGA Version 7.2.2. Teams of 5 doing day to day tasks linked with optimization of application, fixing bugs, doing enhancement, analysing logs, helps in Production

releases etc

Project Title: Royal Bank of Canada Client: Rbc Financial Services Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2016 - Jul 2018 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Upgrade project from Pega version 6.2 to Version 7.1.8.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time